Vod2smi by Blue-Bird™
Benji?
Benji, do you copy?
Shit.
Where is Ethan?
Uh, I can't talk right now.
The package is on the plane.
Yeah, I know.
We're currently formulating a plan B.
Although, technically, it's a plan C.
This isn't going very well.
I am aware of that, Brandt.
You're not helping.
- Where's Ethan?
- I don't know. We're on radio silence.
That plane cannot take off
with the package on it.
- Do you understand?
- We're working on it.
Luther?
What the hell are you doing there?
You're supposed to be
on assignment in Malaysia!
I am in Malaysia.
I've been here two days.
- Benji needed my help.
- I didn't need help.
I needed assistance.
It's a different thing.
The package is still on the plane.
We understand the package
is on the plane.
- We're trying to cripple it remotely.
- You can do that?
We can if the pilot left
the satellite uplink switched on.
Which he has.
- And how do you access the uplink?
- It involves hacking a Russian satellite.
- I can't authorize that.
- Which is why I didn't ask permission.
We're under investigation
for misconduct.
The package is on board.
What do you want me to do?
Uh, Luther.
I'm reading
a heat bloom, Benji.
- The engines are starting.
- Yeah, I'm aware of that.
But I can't do anything
until I'm connected to the satellite.
Benji, you're connected.
Okay, great.
The package is still on that plane.
Shut down the fuel pump.
Uh, the mechanicals
are locked down.
- What about the electrical system?
- Oh, that might work.
Uh, no.
- Hydraulics!
- Okay, stand by.
No, they're encrypted.
Benji, the plane!
Yes! The package is on the plane!
We get it!
Can you open the door?
Ethan? Where are you?
I'm by the plane.
Benji, can you open the door?
Uh, can I open the door? Uh, maybe.
Open the door when I tell you!
I'm on the plane. Open the door.
How did you get in the plane?
Net in the plane.
I'm on the plane!
Open the door!
Benji! Open the door!
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay, okay!
- Benji, open that door right now!
- Yeah, I'm trying!
Come on, Benji!
Benji, open that door!
Come on! Come on!
Come on!
Yes, got it!
That's the wrong door!
Benji, not that door. The other door.
The other door, right!
Yes, the other door.
Okay, yes! Sorry, my bad, my bad!
Check it out.
All right, look, I'm gonna open
the para door! How's that?
Hey! Hey!
We're about to close.
I won't be long.
Are you looking for anything
in particular?
Something rare.
Let me guess.
Classical.
- Jazz.
Sax?
- Coltrane.
- Piano?
Monk.
Shadow Wilson on bass.
Shadow Wilson played drums.
Know why they call him Shadow?
Because he had a light touch.
You're in luck.
I have a first pressing.
It really is you.
I've heard stories.
They can't all be true.
Good evening, Mr. Hunt.
The weapons you recovered in Belarus
were confirmed to be VX nerve gas
capable of devastating a major city.
The bodies of the air crew were found
less than 24 hours
after they landed in Damascus.
They were identified as
low-level Chechen separatists
with neither the access nor the ability
to acquire the weapons
they were transporting.
This would support your suspicion
that a shadow organization
is committed to inciting revolution
by enabling acts of terror
in nations friendly to Western interests.
IMF suspects this to be
the same shadow organization
you have been tracking for the last year,
also known as the Syndicate.
IMF would be right.
Normally, you and your team
would be tasked
with infiltrating and disrupting
this terrorist network.
But we have taken steps to ensure
that this will not happen.
Because we are
the Syndicate, Mr. Hunt.
And now we know who you are.
Your mission, should you choose
to accept it, is to face your fate.
Pursue us, you will be caught.
Resist us, you will be killed.
And your precious Secretary will
disavow any knowledge of your actions.
Good luck, Mr. Hunt.
This message will self-destruct
in five seconds.
Mr. Chairman,
the IMF's misadventures date back
to my earliest days at the CIA
when the IMF broke into the CIA
to steal a list of covert operatives.
And now, more recently,
a Russian warhead?
Disarmed Russian warhead.
- A Russian nuclear warhead...
Rendered safe by the IMF.
clipped the Transamerica Pyramid
before plunging into
the San Francisco Bay.
- Saving the western hemisphere.
- This made possible by IMF agents
who did willingly provide
the launch codes to a known terrorist.
Do I have that right, Agent Brandt?
I can neither confirm nor deny details
of any such operation
without the Secretary's approval.
This was the same week that the IMF
infiltrated the Kremlin.
Here is the Kremlin before
and the Kremlin after.
I can neither confirm nor deny details
of any operation...
Without the Secretary's approval,
yes, we know.
In fact, until this panel appoints
a new Secretary,
you really can't say much of anything,
can you, Agent Brandt?
Well, I didn't write the rules, Mr. Hunley.
Mr.. Chairman,
the so-called Impossible Mission Force
is not just a rogue organization.
It is an outdated one, a throwback
to an era without transparency
- and without oversight.
- Mr. Chairman?
- Time has come to dissolve the IMF...
And transfer their salvageable assets
to the CIA.
Mr. Chairman, the IMF has operated
without oversight for 40 years.
- Mr. Chairman?
- Are its methods unorthodox? Yes.
Are its results less than perfect?
Absolutely.
- But without the IMF...
- There will be order and stability!
Without the IMF...
This panel recognizes
the IMF's contribution to global security.
But the events laid out
by CIA Director Hunley
also show a pattern
of wanton brinkmanship
and a total disregard for protocol.
From where I sit,
your unorthodox methods
are indistinguishable from chance.
And your results, perfect or not,
look suspiciously like luck.
I'm afraid today is the day
when the IMF's luck runs out.
What are you doing here?
Hmm?
I said, what are you doing here?
What does he see in you, I wonder?
Who is he?
I want to see what he's made of.
Well, why don't you
take off the cuffs and I'll show you,
Vinter?
You know who I am.
Janik Vinter.
They call you the Bone Doctor.
The funny thing is,
you were officially declared dead
three years ago.
Nice shoes, by the way.
Not his.
Yours.
Our instructions were to break him down...
not kill him.
Some guys break different than others.
This one's a fighter.
He'll die before you turn him.
Are you worried
he's going to take your place?
You should go before it gets ugly.
Yeah, he's right. You should go.
So now let's see how tough you are.
Janik.
We've never met before, right?
Follow me.
Give me the gun!
- What are you doing?
- I can't leave.
You can't stay.
We just killed those men.
We didn't kill them, you did.
I tried to stop you. You got away.
Who are you?
You better hurry now. Good luck.
No, wait! Wait!
Where is he?
He's heading towards the north passage.
He's closed the gate.
Run. He's getting away. HURRY.
- Satcom seven.
- Western Europe unsecured.
- Designator?
- Bravo-Echo-1-1.
Connecting.
- This is Brandt.
- Go secure.
Go.
London terminal is compromised.
Repeat, London is compromised.
Agent in place is down.
Request immediate extraction.
What happened?
Who breached London?
Do you have anything to go on?
A face.
He wanted something. Not information.
He could've killed me.
But he didn't.
- Okay. What do you think it means?
- The Syndicate is real.
They know who we are, how we operate.
I think I know why
they've been so hard to find.
Just focus operations on gathering
any available intel regarding
former covert operatives.
It doesn't matter
what country or agency,
just as long as they're dead
or presumed dead.
Start with Janik Vinter.
He's also known as the Bone Doctor.
I can't do that.
What? What are you talking about?
The Committee has shut us down.
Operations have been handed over
to the CIA.
There is no more IMF.
I've been ordered to bring everyone in.
- Ethan...
- I understand.
- I understand, Brandt.
We didn't have this conversation.
I've disappeared in London.
You don't know where I am.
If I'm dead or alive.
This man you saw, can you find him?
I won't stop until I do.
This may very well be
our last mission, Ethan.
Make it count.
Brandt?
Since we're going
to be working together,
I want you to choose
your next words very carefully.
Where is Hunt?
- I don't know.
- Don't lie to me, Brandt.
I have no way of contacting him.
He's deep cover.
Last I heard,
he's tracking the Syndicate.
Let's out the bull. You know who we are,
you know what we're capable of.
How come the CIA has never discovered
any actionable intel
regarding this, uh, Syndicate?
- What are you implying?
- Not implying. Stating.
Levelling an accusation, actually.
Hunt is both arsonist and fireman
at the same time.
I believe that the Syndicate
is a figment of his imagination,
created to justify the IMF's existence.
I am going to find him, Brandt,
and when I do,
he will be called upon to answer for
every wanton act of mayhem
he is responsible for.
Welcome to the CIA.
You'll never find him.
Set your watch, Brandt. Ethan Hunt
is living his last day as a free man.
All right, everybody, heads up! This is it.
Alpha team prepped standing by.
Execute.
Langley, Brimstone. Go.
I say again, we are go.
Langley, there's nobody here.
Langley, Brimstone. Face the north wall.
Dunn.
Is it that time already? Okay.
I will ask you
a series of control questions.
I know,
and I'm gonna answer truthfully,
and then you're gonna ask me
to lie intentionally.
- State your name.
- The King of Norway.
See, that's a lie.
I'm actually third in line to the throne.
My brother was...
Has Ethan Hunt contacted you?
Why would he Contact me?
Hunt has resurfaced.
This time in Cuba.
He, uh, left these behind.
Tell me what you make of them.
I don't know. He's taken up
scrap booking?
Look at the photographs, Dunn.
All of them are either missing or dead.
Every one.
All of them were government agents.
Russian, French, British, Israeli,
you name it.
These are highly classified files and yet
Hunt had no trouble collecting them.
And he always seems to be
a step ahead of us.
I wonder how.
- Are you suggesting I'm helping him?
- Oh, the thought had crossed my mind.
Six months I have been here,
sifting through mountains of metadata
and exabytes of encoded excrement.
I have decrypted, processed, parsed
more data than anyone in my section.
And yet, every week you haul me in here
and you ask me the same question,
just in a different way.
And today you haven't answered it.
You seem to think
I have some kind of obligation to him.
Okay. Nothing could be further
from the truth.
Ethan Hunt is still out there in the field,
and I am stuck here answering for it.
We are not friends.
I owe him nothing.
That'll be all, Dunn.
Welcome to Vienna, Benji Miss me?
Ethan, where are you?
Where the hell have you been?
You know what?
Please, don't tell me that.
Because it's just another thing I'll have
to lie about in my weekly polygraph.
Everything's gonna be fine.
Just keep walking.
But make sure
you're not being followed.
I didn't win those opera tickets, did I?
No, I'm afraid not.
- So, where do we meet?
- We don't.
For your sake,
we shouldn't be seen together.
You have mail.
Who is he?
That's what
we're here to find out.
What I do know is he's our
only possible link to the Syndicate.
And I have reason to believe
he's going to be here tonight.
But I can't find him alone. Are you in?
- Uh...
- Are you in?
Yes, of course. Of course. Um...
So what's the play?
Simple. You find him. We tag him.
I follow him wherever he goes.
And after that?
After that, you're on a plane.
Back at work Monday morning.
No one is the wiser.
- Wait, that's it?
- You he in enough danger as it is.
I didn't want to involve you this much,
but I had no choice.
Well, if you're going to bring me
all this way,
you could at least give me something
a bit more, you know, dramatic.
Benji, we're trying to keep a low profile.
You want drama, go to the opera.
- Are you seeing what I'm seeing?
- Yes, I am.
Am I correct in assuming
that is the Chancellor of Austria?
Yes, you are.
Did you know
he was going to be here?
No.
Right. Well, we have
a European head of state here
at the same time as we are looking
for a nefarious terrorist.
And I'm sure that the two things
are completely unrelated.
Benji.
Meanwhile, I will try and overlook
the fact that
you're an international fugitive
wanted by the CIA!
And that this little unsanctioned
operation is tantamount to treason.
Because, as you stated earlier, I will be
back at my desk on Monday morning,
playing video games,
and no one will be any the wiser.
- The show's about to start, Benji.
- Right.
Just take your position.
- Tell me What you see.
- Okay.
Nice tux, by the way.
Lights ready, Act One preset.
Final preparations complete.
Everyone standby please.
Join the IMF! See the world!
On a monitor. In a closet.
Okay, I have eyes.
Searching.
Talk to me, Benji.
Nothing yet. Stand by.
I know you're here. Where are you?
Uh, Ethan, I might have
something for you. Can't confirm.
- Where?
- Backstage. I'll direct you.
Take the door on your left.
He should be right in front of you.
Benji, do you see that?
See what?
- That woman.
- What woman? Where are you?
I can't see you.
What was that?
I don't know.
Oh! Ah!
Ethan, do you copy? Ethan, come in!
Ethan, the lighting booth!
Ethan, do you copy?
It's just a flesh wound.
Seal the building. Close the exits.
I have a way out. Interested?
Lead the way.
- Anything you want to tell me?
- Uh, no, not right now.
- How's the pace?
- Don't wait for me.
What's next?
There.
Shoes.
Shoes, please.
Uh...
If anything were to happen to you...
Nothing's going to happen to me.
Get in!
Go, go, go.
What the... She tried to shoot me!
That doesn't make her a bad person.
I'm going to have to Search you.
- You have to let me go.
- Oh. Not a chance!
I assumed you were deep cover
back in London,
but isn't this taking
the role a little far?
Hang on a minute. Do you know her?
We haven't been formally introduced,
but I'm pretty sure
she's British intelligence?
Ilsa Faust. You're Ethan Hunt.
And that shade is very hard to find.
What were you doing
at the opera tonight?
Aside from killing the Chancellor.
Saving your life in London
put me in a tight spot
with some very dangerous people.
I was sent to kill the Chancellor
to regain their trust.
Ah, so you admit that you killed him!
I went through the motions.
That's not the same thing.
You thought you'd put him
in the hospital,
take him out of harm's way.
Same thing you tried to do.
You're not going to
believe that, are you?
What about the rest of her team?
You mean those other two idiots.
I can only assume
they were redundancies.
In case you didn't follow through.
One man to kill the Chancellor,
the other one to kill you.
- A test.
- Second one I've failed, thanks to you.
And the car bomb was insurance.
Uh, we have a tail.
Who is he?
We're after the same thing,
and I can help you.
If you want to bring down the Syndicate,
you have to let me out.
Uh, they're closing!
This has to look like an escape,
so you just throw me out anywhere.
Tell me who he is.
Whoa!
Change of plan! Throw her out!
You have everything you need
to find me.
Less than 24 hours
after we interviewed Benji Dunn
about Ethan Hunt,
he was on a plane to Vienna
with tickets to the opera.
And within six hours of his arrival,
the Chancellor was dead.
Now, that might be circumstance
to some public defender,
but to the CIA,
that is actionable intelligence.
Consider for the moment
the possibility that.
Ethan's investigation
led him to the opera,
and that he's the one
with the actionable intelligence!
In any case, finding Hunt
is no longer a pet project.
The Special Activities Division
will now have full discretion.
You mean shoot to kill.
Whether Hunt lives or dies
is entirely up to him.
New identity.
Passport, cash, move map.
There's a change of clothes
in that bag right there.
Everything you need
to make it to D.C. undetected.
Once you're there,
you have to inform on me.
- I'm sorry, what?
- Just tell the truth.
You came to Vienna believing
you won two tickets to the opera.
I attempted to recruit you
into assassinating the Chancellor.
- You refused.
- That's not the truth!
Your life depends on
them believing you, Benji.
It'll go easier
if you tell them what they want to hear.
Ethan, at least tell me
what this is all about.
You recognize anyone?
Him.
He's former KSA. German intelligence.
Missing, presumed dead.
He was at the opera tonight.
This one, too.
Former Mossad.
Let me guess. Presumed dead.
Tonight, I made it official.
I was looking for him in the Bosphorus.
The same day, a car accident
killed the visiting President of Malawi.
He slipped away again in Jakarta,
hours before a passenger plane
vanished over the Pacific
with 238 passengers.
I just missed him in the Philippines
right before a fire
at a petrochemical plant
gassed a village of 2,000 people.
You're saying these accidents
are somehow connected.
That missing plane was carrying
the Secretary of the World Bank.
That fire bankrupted
a global arms corporation.
That wreck triggered a civil war.
These are no accidents.
They're links in a chain.
The work of a single organization,
the Syndicate.
A rogue nation,
trained to do what we do,
imbued with a new sense of purpose.
Destroy the system that created them
regardless of who's in their way.
An anti-IMF.
Since Hunley shut us down,
they've been escalating unchecked.
Killing the Chancellor tonight
was a statement,
the start of a new phase.
Or they could just be
a series of random disasters.
He was there.
Every time.
Just like he was there tonight,
I'm sure of it.
I don't know who he is, where he's from,
how he's funded.
But I know he's the key.
Ethan, this is what I signed up for.
Let me help you find him.
That's why I brought you here
in the first place,
and look what happened!
I can't protect you.
That's why I need you to leave.
That's not your decision to make, Ethan!
I am afield agent. I know the risks.
More than that, I am your friend,
no matter what I tell
the polygraph every week.
Now, you called me
because you needed my help.
And you still do. So I am staying.
And that is all
we are going to say about that.
Okay.
Good.
Where do we start?
Ilsa.
Right. And how do we find her?
She said we have everything we need.
We had an agreement.
You send me to do a job, I do it.
But my way, not yours.
Where did I deviate?
You put two more gunmen
at the opera tonight.
One of them tried to kill me.
You missed.
I missed because Ethan Hunt was there
looking for you.
Ethan Hunt's in Vienna because
you allowed him to escape in London.
Vinter would have killed him in London,
and that's not what you asked for.
Twice now you've let him slip away.
Curious.
Are you questioning my loyalty
or my ability?
- Can't decide.
- I've told you before, trust me or kill me.
But if you're going to kill me, be a man.
Do it yourself.
Did he say anything?
He knows about Morocco.
What does he know about Morocco?
He knows about the power plant.
He doesn't know what's in it.
Find him, please.
He'll find me.
I've seen to that.
That's interesting.
- What is it?
- It's a skiff.
A secure computer facility.
Offline, ultra-contained.
It's impossible to hack into
from the outside.
It's essentially
a digital safety deposit box.
Very strange thing for a young lady
to be carrying in her sundries.
Where's it located?
Uh...
Morocco.
And what brings you gentlemen
to Casablanca?
Good to see you.
What couldn't you tell me
over the phone?
The Chancellor of Austria
was assassinated.
We believe that
Ethan and Benji were there.
Hunley has handed this over
to the Special Activities Division.
We need to find Ethan before they do.
And that's where you come in.
Not interested.
- Okay, look, Luther...
- Look, man, I know Ethan.
I don't know you.
All I know about you
is that you chose to work for Hunley.
Yeah. All I know about you
is you chose to resign.
You don't have to worry
about Ethan. They'll never catch him.
No, they're not gonna catch him. No.
This is the CIA.
This is Hunley we're talking about.
Things are out of control.
No, they're going to kill him.
They're going to kill Ethan.
They're going to kill Benji.
We have to get to them first.
Are you going to help me?
You need to understand something.
Ethan is my friend.
And if I have one second of doubt
whose side you're on...
Mmm?
I believe you.
- All right.
What do I have to go on?
Not much. And not a lot of time.
His name is Solomon Lane.
He created the Syndicate.
Where does he come from?
He's former British intelligence.
Well, if British intelligence knows
the Syndicate exists,
why don't they just tell the CIA?
Because they don't want
anyone knowing
the Syndicate was created
by one of their own.
I was sent undercover
to earn Lane's trust
and eventually identify the members
of his organization.
And for the first time in two years,
I'm close to knowing who they are.
Lane had a ledger.
It contained the identities of
his operatives, his terrorist associates,
the entire inner workings
of the Syndicate.
One of his agents stole it,
hoping to blackmail him,
and kept it in a secure computer facility
for safekeeping.
He died being interrogated
for the access code,
leaving Lane with a serious problem.
So the key to crushing Lane
is sitting in a computer,
just waiting for someone to take it.
So, why hasn't Lane
just sent someone to steal it?
Oh, he has.
He sent me.
And I can tell you
it's impossible.
The facility's hidden beneath
a local power plant under military guard.
And the only way to download the ledger
is through the central
computer terminal, located there.
To reach the terminal,
you'll need to pass the main gate,
access the elevator
with fingerprint recognition,
and open
three separate combination locks.
BENJ: Well, that's easy.
We just impersonate the agent
who stole the ledger in the first place,
and I get to wear a mask!
Unfortunately, even if you could
make it through
every other security measure,
you won't beat the last one.
That's because it's protected
by gait analysis.
The step beyond facial recognition.
These cameras actually know
how the agent walks,
how he talks, how he moves.
Right down to his facial tics.
So, what you're saying is
no mask can beat it.
We're busted before we even get
into the vault,
and I wind up in a Moroccan jail,
playing mummies and daddies
with Ahmad the Strangler.
Okay, I don't get to wear a mask.
And there's no other way
into the computer lab?
No other way in.
- Air shaft?
- Six-inch-diameter pipe.
Foundation?
Twelve feet of concrete, top and bottom.
- Electrical conduit.
Bottom line is there's no way
into that terminal
unless your profile is pre-installed
in the security system.
Profile.
Where are the profiles stored?
All security data is stored offline
in the liquid-cooled array.
Here, inside the torus.
Liquid-cooled.
You mean that thing is underwater?
- Yes.
Okay. So, to get the ledger,
one of us needs to enter the torus
and change the security profile,
so that the other one can access
the computer without being caught.
- That's the only way.
Can I get in through there? What's that?
That's the service hatch.
It can only be opened from the inside.
If you try and open it from the outside,
you'd be hit with 70,000 gallons
of pressurized water.
Where does the water come from?
Desalinated seawater flows through
the intake, in the power plant.
And, before you ask, the system
is designed to shut down automatically
if any metal enters the intake.
No oxygen tanks.
All right.
Well, how long will it take to free swim
from the intake to the service hatch?
Two minutes,
with the current at full power.
Then you just have to hold your breath
for two minutes.
What about installing
the security profile?
Well, that's gonna be, like,
a minute, tops.
So I have to hold my breath
for three minutes.
You can do that.
What I think you're overlooking
is the physical exertion.
The more you exert yourself,
the faster you consume oxygen.
Don't worry about him, all right? All he
has to do is install the fake profile
before I get to the gait analysis.
You said it yourself, it's the only way.
That doesn't sound impossible.
Satellite over watch
covering all seven continents.
DNA profiling, facial recognition,
drone surveillance, drone strikes.
So, how are we supposed to find
Ethan and Benji before they do?
I'm not even looking for them.
I'm looking for her.
What do you mean?
These sketches. What do you see?
Ethan's not exactly sure
who this guy is.
But this woman...
- He knows her.
- He trusts her.
I'm betting that if he's not already
with her, he's on his way.
Find her, find Ethan.
Tell me it's possible to pull
facial recognition off a sketch.
For mere mortals, no.
- For me, I could've done this at home.
- All right.
- How long is this gonna take?
- Found her.
CCTV picked her up
at the airport in Casablanca.
What the hell?
She's bad news.
Sorry.
Your' card isn't working.
Benji we're in.
One more time.
You'll have three minutes.
Two and a half minutes
to switch the security profile.
Thirty seconds to escape
through the service hatch.
Remember, conserve oxygen.
Don't move a muscle
if you don't have to.
I'm in the elevator.
That current will carry you
to the torus.
Once you're there, I'll shut it down.
Important note.
The profile is in slot 108.
And a slightly more important note.
If you haven't switched that profile
before I reach the gait analysis,
I'm dead.
Thank you, Benji.
What's the problem?
The cooling system's rebooting by itself.
All systems normal.
Cooling system's at full power.
No, no, no.
You're all right.
Oh, you're okay.
You see? What did I tell you?
Difficult? Absolutely. But certainly not...
Jesus. Is he all right? What happened?
Okay.
Here.
Hey.
I misjudged you.
Hey, man. You okay? How you doing?
Hey, buddy.
- Benji.
- Yeah, Benji. You did good.
You take a moment, all right?
Just take a moment.
There's nothing a little sunshine
and fresh air won't fix.
- You'll be right as rain.
- What are you doing here?
Look, look.
We got it.
I knew we'd get it.
Listen, I don't want to
sound ungrateful, okay?
I appreciate everything you do for me,
But one of these days,
you're going to take it too far.
We got it!
We're gonna nail that...
Wait, wait...
I thought you said
you could find him.
I said I could locate him.
- You have to find him.
- Right.
Where's Hunt?
He's dead.
That really hurts!
- Can you walk?
- Yes.
We have to get to her before Lane does.
Whoa. Whoa.
Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
Are you okay to drive?
A minute ago you were dead.
What are you talking about?
This is not going to end well.
There she is!
Stairs, stairs, stairs!
Ah! God damn it!
Whoa.
We found him.
Oh, come on, man!
Shit!
It's a high-speed chase!
You just had to get the four-by-four,
didn't you?
- Don't blame me. You chose the car.
- You just had to have it!
- Do you want me to drive?
Look at this thing!
Look how slow you're going.
Speed it up!
Who's this guy?
Shit!
Oh!
Ahhh!
Go! Go! Go!
I'm okay! I'm okay! I'm okay!
Whoa!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Whoa! Whoa!
Here they come!
What are we gonna do?
Uh...
Gun!
- Do you have your seatbelt on?
- You're asking me that now?
'Hang on!
We good?
Things got a little out of hand.
Ah! Look out!
We're good?
Oh, hey, boys, what did I miss?
Ooh, that looks sharp. Careful! Careful!
So what do we do now?
Please tell me
you made a copy of that disk.
Of course I made a copy.
So where are we going?
It's a ledger.
The Syndicate's entire infrastructure.
Who they are,
the politicians they control,
and where the money comes from.
It's everything you want to know.
What makes you think
this so-called ledger is authentic?
Why would Lane want it so badly
if it wasn't authentic?
Why would he ever
let you have it if it was?
Did you never stop to consider
that he may want me to have it?
Misinformation, manipulation,
it's what he does, Ilsa.
It's what he's trained to do.
Lane lies to you,
you sell these lies to Hunt.
Together, you're both compromised.
That's his ultimate objective.
This may be authentic.
But there's only one person I trust
to verify that information. You.
No.
My orders were to deliver you
information regarding the Syndicate.
Your orders were
to infiltrate the Syndicate
that we may learn more
about them first hand.
This isn't proof.
It's a test, like everything else.
The only way to pass is to go back.
I can't do that. I've betrayed Lane's trust
too many times.
And in every instance,
you did so on your own volition.
He was going to torture and kill
an American agent.
And you should have let him.
Then you would still have Lane's trust.
This is the trade. Hunt understands that.
I wasn't going to let him die.
He's our ally.
There are no allies in statecraft, Ilsa,
only common interests.
As it stands, Ethan Hunt is a man
without a country.
This makes killing him
decidedly less complicated.
Are you ordering me to kill Hunt?
Good God, no.
Nothing so crude as that. No.
Lane will order you.
And to regain his trust,
you will do it.
You sent me to do a job. I did it.
Now you bring me in!
Might I remind you,
you are without a country of your own?
The Director of the CIA called me,
inquiring about you personally.
Of course, to protect your cover,
I had to lie.
So, as far as the Americans
are concerned,
you're a rogue assassin,
a target of opportunity.
Precious few people know
about your true identity.
It would be unfortunate if we forgot.
You see, there really is no choice, Ilsa.
You're going back.
Glad to know you're still with us.
What's happening?
I can't open it.
- What do you mean, you can't open it?
- I mean I can't open it, ever.
That's a red box.
- A what?
- It's a red box.
The British government uses them
to transport state secrets.
- Doesn't sound good.
- Meaning it's triple-encrypted.
You're not getting into that thing
unless you have fingerprints,
retinal scan,
and a voice phrase spoken
by a specific individual.
The Prime Minister
of Great Britain himself.
Yes, him.
So what you're saying is
there is no ledger,
which means we have no proof
that the Syndicate even exists.
So we're back to square one,
only now we are all wanted by the CIA.
I'm so proud of us.
What I don't understand is
why is there a red box
sat in a private data vault in Morocco?
And why would Lane want it
if he can't open it?
If Lane wants it,
you can bet he has a plan to open it.
And we just helped him steal it.
He's going to take the Prime Minister.
Yes, he is. The question is how.
Well, we have to warn
the British government.
Yeah, MI6.
No, Brandt. Put down the phone.
Let's think about this for a minute.
We have a responsibility
to warn the British government
and not gamble
with the Prime Minister's life, Ethan,
just so you can beat the guy
that has beaten you at every turn.
Is that what you think this is?
Brandt?
I think right now you're incapable
of seeing that there is another way.
And sometimes Ethan is the only one
capable of seeing the only way.
And if he is wrong,
then we have Vienna all over again!
You don't know him.
If he wants something to happen,
there is no preventing it!
That's why we have to warn the British.
Maybe that's exactly
what he wants us to do.
Are you listening to yourself?
We are going to warn the British.
No. We're going to find Lane,
we're going to get him,
before he takes the Prime Minister.
Okay.
All right, Ethan.
We're going to find Lane.
But please tell me
how are we going to do that?
All is forgiven.
That isn't a ledger, is it?
You didn't take a look for yourself?
Of course I did,
but the file was encrypted.
And why would I lie to you?
So that I would lie to Hunt.
But he wouldn't have stolen it
if he knew what it was.
And you wouldn't have helped him.
What is actually on that disk?
I'll be honest with you
when you start being honest with me.
Now, you and I both know
why you've come back. Don't we?
Hmm?
You're still alive
because I believe in your potential.
But I'm growing impatient.
Why do you continue to resist?
Well, if we're being honest,
you're a terrorist.
If that were true,
my goal would be to spread fear.
But my method is far more surgical.
You kill innocent people.
I helped my government kill
many innocent people and more.
So much more.
Killing to keep things as they were.
And now I'm killing
to bring about change.
I think Ethan Hunt would disagree.
Ethan Hunt is a gambler.
And one day his luck will run out,
and thousands of innocent people
will pay the price.
Which one of us will be the villain then?
Nothing here. It's empty.
I'm interested to see who you blame
for what happens next.
So that's her?
That's her.
I have to say you sure can ride.
- Ethan...
- You were just doing your job.
That's all we're going to say about it.
Atlee said you would understand.
Atlee.
Your handler in British intelligence.
And he didn't bring you in,
even after you gave him the disk.
You knew perfectly well it was blank.
That's a lie..
The disk she took from me
was an exact copy. I'm sure of it.
Was it in your possession
the entire time?
They don't care if you live or die.
But you knew
I was going to take it to him.
I hoped you would.
I hoped it'd be enough to get you out.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. That means
Lane doesn't have the disk. Only we do.
I have a question.
If the disk was blank,
why is she still alive?
Unless, of course,
Lane wanted us to find her.
So who you working for now?
Lane, Atlee, your government,
my government, they're all the same.
We only think
we're fighting for the right side
because that's what
we choose to believe.
So where does that leave us?
The way I see it,
you have three choices.
One, you hand me
and the disk over to the CIA.
I am proof the Syndicate exists.
Lane becomes their problem
and your work is done.
- My thoughts exactly.
- Works for me.
But you know
they're not gonna believe you.
And you'll all be tried for treason.
Lane goes free.
I'm afraid she has a point.
Two, you let me walk away
to an uncertain fate.
You use the disk as bait to trap Lane.
But some part of you suspects
you've met your match.
And being a gambler, you'll probably
end up handing Lane that disk,
whether you want to or not.
That is entirely possible.
And option three?
Come away with me.
Right now.
Oh, boy.
And what about Lane?
Forget about Lane.
There will always be another Lane.
There will always be people like us
to face him.
We've done our part
and we've been cast aside.
We can be anyone.
We can do anything.
It's only a matter of going.
Lane sent you to deliver a message,
didn't he?
I've saved your life twice.
I won't be able to do it again.
What's the message?
Benji.
Parking garage.
Luther, stay with her!
She's gone. I lost her.
She set us up, Ethan.
No. She delivered a message.
She set us up!
She knew this would happen!
Only Lane knows
what's going to happen!
I have a job for you, Ethan.
And for the sake of your friend,
you will do it.
I'm listening.
Your mission,
should you choose to accept it,
is to bring me the unlocked disk
by midnight tonight.
New say the words, please.
I accept.
Yes.
I knew you would.
He wants the disk, unlocked,
by midnight tonight.
Ethan, there's only one person on Earth
who can unlock that disk.
We have to take the Prime Minister.
Let's just think about that
for a minute.
It's the only way to get Benji back.
Ethan, that's exactly
what Lane wants you to do.
Which is why it has to happen.
This is how we beat Lane.
This is how we make everything right.
Can you see?
Can't you see it?
William Brandt, sir. He says it's urgent.
I had a feeling
you'd come to your senses, Brandt.
I'm only calling you
because I have no other choice.
I'm trying to prevent a catastrophe.
I can understand that. Where are you?
- London.
- Reroute us to London now.
- Where in London?
- I'll tell you when you land, not before.
I'm not interested
in playing games, Brandt.
And I'm not interested
in seeing my friends get killed either.
So if I'm going to betray them,
we're going do this on my terms
and my terms only. Do you understand?
Keep your phone on.
Instructions will follow.
You should've been gone
by now.
Yeah.
You okay?
We're supposed to take down
the Prime Minister
of Great Britain tonight.
So...
Brandt?
I can't see another way.
Neither can I.
But we do what we have to do
for our friends, right?
Get him ready, please.
You were right to call me, Brandt.
Where is Hunt?
He's on his way.
We don't have much time.
- What does he intend to do?
- What matters is that he's alive.
And I need your reassurance
that he's going to stay that way.
Have you informed
the British government
that Hunt has targeted
the Prime Minister?
I will help you capture him alive.
That is the deal.
You've picked up some terrible habits
from your friend, Brandt,
the worst of them being that you still
believe you can control any outcome.
Stay with him.
Chief Atlee! Chief Atlee.
Director Hunley,
how delightful to see you here.
Last time we spoke, you were hunting
rogue agents in Morocco.
Chief Atlee, I have reason to believe that
the Prime Minister's life is in danger.
I'm listening.
AUCTIONEER: Any advance
on 22,000? Anyone?
Going once. Going twice.
Sold to our generous chairwoman.
Sir? Chief Atlee from MI6
needs to see you.
He says it's urgent.
Excuse me.
What's this all about?
It's a matter of national security, sir.
Under no circumstances
is anyone to enter.
Yes, sir.
Help me to understand.
Who is this man? Why is he after me?
I'm afraid, Prime Minister,
Director Hunley and I
share responsibility for this.
Ethan Hunt was part of
a disgraced intelligence agency
which has since been dissolved.
And he's gone rogue,
unfortunately intent on dismantling
an imaginary terror network.
But new intelligence suggests
he's been manipulated
by one of your own former agents.
Ilsa Faust, Prime Minister.
She disappeared two years ago.
If you don't mind my asking, what do
I have to do with this phantom network?
Uh, sir, this is William Brandt,
a former colleague of Hunt's.
He came forward with first hand
knowledge of the plot against you.
Sir, Hunt is in possession
of a virtual red box
that can only be opened by you.
He believes it is the key
to bring down the Syndicate.
The Syndicate, you say?
Yes, sir.
That's what he calls it.
Atlee?
He couldn't possibly be talking about
that Syndicate.
Because you assured me that
that Syndicate was merely an exercise.
And it was, Prime Minister,
I can assure you.
And yet here we have
the Central Intelligence Agency
indicating otherwise.
I don't understand.
Prime Minister, your life is in danger.
I think our first priority is to move you
to a secure location.
Sir, does the name Solomon Lane
ring a bell?
Yes.
Unfortunately, it does.
So there actually is a Syndicate?
It was the hypothetical brainchild
of Chief Atlee.
Recruit former agents
from other nations,
supply them with a new identity,
and use them to surgically remove
our enemies, both at home and abroad.
Its operating budget
was to be hidden offshore
in a virtual red box
which I alone would control.
It would have made me
judge, jury, and executioner,
with zero accountability.
I rejected the proposal, unequivocally.
Furthermore,
I was given every assurance
it never passed the planning stage.
Prime Minister, there is no Syndicate.
These men have been duped
by Agent Faust.
Atlee! Save it for the public inquiry.
Sir, I urge you not to leave this room.
- Excuse me.
- Please.
Hunt is uniquely trained
and highly motivated.
A specialist without equal,
immune to any countermeasures.
There is no secret he cannot extract.
No security he cannot breach.
No person he cannot become.
He has, most likely,
anticipated this very conversation
and is waiting to strike
in whatever direction we move.
Sir, Hunt is the living manifestation
of destiny.
And he has made you his mission.
Prime Minister?
Hunt.
Sir, please step away
from the Prime Minister.
Just relax, sir.
Everything's going to be all right.
- Atlee shot me.
- Yes, he did, sir.
Hunt, I hope you realize you've set back
US-UK relations
to the American Revolution?
Desperate times,
desperate measures, sir.
I'm here.
- Stand by to receive.
- Ready.
The Prime Minister's office asked me
to meet him here.
This way, sir.
Scanning.
Retinal scan confirmed.
Mmm.
It's okay. Here you go, sir.
You've got a very warm hand.
Biometric confirmed.
The prompt is Kipling.
Sir, I'm going to need a pass-phrase.
Yes, of course.
If you can keep your head when
all about you are losing theirs...
If you can trust yourself
when all men doubt you...
- You got it?
- I got it.
Oh, man, do I got it.
I'm here to see the Prime Minister.
We were told not to let anybody in.
- By Whom?
- By you, sir.
Hunley? What is this?
Security!
Chief Atlee.
Kind of you to accept our invitation.
Ah.
Do you know who I am?
We know you created the Syndicate.
But Lane went rogue
and turned it against you, didn't he?
And you've been
desperately trying to cover it up.
That's why you erased the disk
when she brought it to you.
That's true.
Now, Director Hunley has some
questions for you regarding Ilsa Faust.
Namely, how you framed her.
That's also true.
It's the antidote.
When the Prime Minister found out
about the Syndicate,
Atlee attacked him.
Yes, that's true.
And then you saved
the Prime Minister, sir.
Did he?
I'm very grateful.
Sir.
You're cutting it very close, Ethan.
I have what you want. Where do I go?
Ethan, wait.
If I'm not there in 15 minutes,
he'll kill Benji.
The mission
is to bring down the Syndicate.
If Lane gets his hands on that money,
we're unleashing a terrorist superpower.
He'll never take me alive.
I'll make sure of it.
And what happens,
Ethan, if you can't make it back?
I'll make it back.
Just be ready.
Greetings, Prime Minister.
If you are viewing this message,
it means that you have chosen
to activate the Syndicate.
This disk gives you access
to 82.4 billion
in untraceable currency
that will allow the Syndicate
to operate undetected for decades.
Instructions to access these funds
are as follows.
This is the end, Mr. Hunt.
Careful.
Two pounds of Semtex.
Five hundred .30 calibre ball bearings.
Your friend is sitting on
a highly sensitive...
pressure trigger.
So no sudden moves.
Your final test.
When Lane has what he wants,
I kill you and Benji.
If not, everyone dies.
No time to think, Ethan.
Have a seat, please.
Human nature. My weapon of choice.
From the moment I killed the young lady
in the record shop,
- I knew you would...
- stop at nothing to catch me.
I also knew Ilsa wouldn't have a choice.
Whether she broke you
that night you met or let you go,
whether you let her run in Morocco,
whether she went to Atlee or not...
You were certain we'd end up
where we are right now.
Then, again,
so was I.
I know you, Lane.
Somewhere along the line,
you had a crisis of faith.
Human life didn't matter any more.
Or maybe it never really did.
Either way,
you killed too many innocent people
without ever asking
who was giving the orders or why.
You blame the system for what you are,
instead of yourself.
You wanted revenge,
but Rome wasn't destroyed in a day.
You needed help.
You needed money, a lot of it.
And you'll stop at nothing to get it.
That's how I know
I'm going to put you in a box.
Where's the disk?
Where is the disk?
You like to play games.
I have a game for you.
I'll give you $50 million
to let Benji go.
Where is the disk?
You're looking at it.
I am the disk.
I memorized it.
All £24 billion in numbered accounts.
If that vest goes off, you get nothing.
Without this money, you're nothing.
Without me, you're nothing.
Right now, you're thinking it's a bluff.
I'd never let my friends die.
I couldn't possibly memorize
the entire disk.
There's only one way to be sure.
Let Benji go.
Take him.
They come one step closer, shoot me.
Stop!
You remember I told you one day
you were going to take things too far?
This is me speaking, by the way,
it's not him.
The only way this ends is you and me,
Lane, face to face.
Only this time,
I won't be locked in a glass box.
You want your money?
The Bone Doctor
is going to have to
beat it out of me!
Now let Benji go.
1-3-9...
- Go.
- Ethan...
Brandt and Luther are waiting. Go.
What do I do?
Kill the woman.
I need Hunt alive.
- Go.
- It's Benji. Where am I going?
- They're coming.
- We're not ready.
Then get ready.
Which way?
Now let's see what you're made of.
Face to face, just as you wished, Ethan.
It hurts, I know.
Gentlemen, this is Solomon Lane.
Mr. Lane,
meet the IMF.
You're free now.
Where will you go?
I don't know.
I've done my part.
Yeah.
Ethan, we got to go!
You'd better hurry now.
Good luck.
You know how to find me.
Director Hunley?
Director Hunley!
Uh, Mr. Chairman.
Six months ago,
you stood before this panel
and demanded that
the IMF be dissolved.
That is correct, sir.
How do you explain
your testimony today?
It's quite simple, really.
We had reason to believe that
the Syndicate had infiltrated
our government at the highest level.
In order for our man
to infiltrate that organization,
his cover had to be absolute.
The whole operation was known
only to myself
and a handful of IMF agents.
So the shuttering of the IMF
was all part of an elaborate scheme
to expose the so-called Syndicate.
That is correct, sir.
Which is why you're here today
asking for the IMF to be reinstated.
That is correct, sir.
I'm not sure the Committee approves
of your methods, Director Hunley.
Uh, desperate times,
desperate measures, Mr. Chairman.
And you, Mr. Brandt,
how can you justify this deception?
I can neither confirm nor deny
details of any operation
without the Secretary's approval.
Welcome to the IMF,
Mr. Secretary.
Modify by Blue-Bird™